<bill session="113" type="s" number="130" updated="2013-03-15T15:45:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Powell Shooting Range Land Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal land to the Powell Recreation District in the State of Wyoming.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2013-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-01-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2013-03-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/24/2013--Introduced.
Powell Shooting Range Land Conveyance Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Powell Recreation District in Wyoming, without consideration, the land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in the Wind River District and identified as the Powell Gun Club for use as: (1) a shooting range, or (2) for any other public purpose consistent with the uses allowed under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act. Instructs the Secretary to require the District to pay all survey and other administrative costs necessary for the preparation and completion of any patents for, and transfers of title to, such land. Requires the District to agree in writing to: (1) pay administrative costs associated with such conveyance, including the costs of environmental, wildlife, cultural, or historical resources studies; and (2) release and indemnify the United States from claims or liabilities that may arise from the uses carried out on such land on or before this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
