<bill session="113" type="h" number="685" updated="2013-03-15T04:47:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">American Fighter Aces Congressional Gold Medal Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To award a Congressional Gold Medal to the American Fighter Aces, collectively, in recognition of their heroic military service and defense of our country's freedom throughout the history of aviation warfare.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400206"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412584" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2013-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2013-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2013--Introduced.
American Fighter Aces Congressional Gold Medal Act - Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate to arrange for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a single gold medal in honor of the American Fighter Aces, collectively, in recognition of their heroic military service and defense of our country's freedom, which has spanned the history of aviation warfare. Requires that, following such award, the medal be given to the Smithsonian Institution for display and research. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian should make the medal available for display elsewhere, particularly at locations associated with the American Fighter Aces, and that preference should be given to locations affiliated with the Smithsonian.</summary>
</bill>
