<bill session="113" type="s" number="27" updated="2013-02-03T15:47:19-05:00">
  <state datetime="2013-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Hill Creek Cultural Preservation and Energy Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to clarify authority granted under the Act entitled "An Act to define the exterior boundary of the Uintah and Ouray Indian Reservation in the State of Utah, and for other purposes".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-01-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="356"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/2013--Introduced.
Hill Creek Cultural Preservation and Energy Development Act - Authorizes Utah to relinquish for the benefit of the Ute Indian Tribe of the Uintah and Ouray Reservation certain of its school trust or subsurface mineral lands south of the border between Grand County and Uintah County, Utah, in exchange for certain federal subsurface mineral lands north of that border. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to reserve an overriding interest in that portion of the mineral estate composed of minerals subject to leasing under the Mineral Leasing Act in the mineral lands conveyed to Utah. Delineates the extent of that interest. Requires Utah to reserve, for the benefit of its school trust, an overriding interest in that portion of the mineral estate composed of minerals subject to leasing under the Mineral Leasing Act in the mineral lands it relinquished to the federal government. Delineates the extent of that interest.</summary>
</bill>
