<bill session="113" type="s" number="374" updated="2013-03-14T18:46:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-03-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Protecting Responsible Gun Sellers Act of 2013</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Fix Gun Checks Act of 2013</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">A bill to ensure that all individuals who should be prohibited from buying a firearm are listed in the national instant criminal background check system and require a background check for every firearm sale.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-02-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2013-03-12">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-03-12">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-03-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="25">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 25.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2013--Introduced.
Protecting Responsible Gun Sellers Act of 2013 - Declares that: (1) Congress supports the right to bear arms, found in the Second Amendment to the Constitution, and the existing prohibition on a national firearms registry; (2) the Department of Justice (DOJ) should make it a top priority to work with states to swiftly input missing records, including mental health records, in the background check system; and (3) if U.S. citizens agree that in order to promote safe and responsible gun ownership, criminals and the mentally ill should be prohibited from possessing firearms, it should be incumbent upon all citizens to ensure weapons are not being transferred to such people.</summary>
</bill>
