<?xml version="1.0"?>
<body status="enr" difference-size-chars="701" percent-change="36" total-changes="9" previous-status="ats">
  <p nid="t0:enr:1">S<removed sequence="1">CON 3 ATS<p/><center><p nid="t0:ats:2">113th CONGRESS</p></center><p/><center><p nid="t0:ats:3">1st Session</p></center><p/><center><p nid="t0:ats:4">S. CON. RES. 3</p></center><p nid="t0:ats:5">Providing for a conditional adjournment or recess of the Senate and an adjournment of the House of Representatives.</p><p/>IN THE SENATE OF</removed><inserted sequence="2">.Con.Res.3</inserted></p>
  <inserted sequence="3">
    <p nid="t0:enr:2">Agreed to January 4, 2013</p>
    <p nid="t0:enr:3">
      <em>
        <center>
          <p nid="t0:enr:4">One Hundred Thirteenth Congress</p>
        </center>
      </em>
    </p>
    <p nid="t0:enr:5">
      <em>
        <center>
          <p nid="t0:enr:6">of the</p>
        </center>
      </em>
    </p>
    <p nid="t0:enr:7">
      <em>
        <center>
          <p nid="t0:enr:8">United States of America</p>
        </center>
      </em>
    </p>
  </inserted>
  <p nid="t0:enr:9">
    <em>
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:enr:10"><inserted sequence="4">AT</inserted> THE <removed sequence="5">UNITED STATES<p/><h3 nid="t0:ats:7"><center><p nid="t0:ats:8">January 3, 2013</p></center></h3><p nid="t0:ats:9">Mr. REID (for himself and Mr. MCCONNELL) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was considered and agreed to</p><hr/><p/><center><p nid="t0:ats:10">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</p></center><p nid="t0:ats:11">Providing for a conditional adjournment or recess of the Senate and an adjournment of the House of Representatives.</p></removed><inserted sequence="6">FIRST SESSION</inserted></p>
      </center>
    </em>
  </p>
  <inserted sequence="7">
    <p nid="t0:enr:11">Begun and held at the City of Washington on Thursday,</p>
    <p nid="t0:enr:12">the third day of January, two thousand and thirteen</p>
    <p nid="t0:enr:13">Concurrent Resolution</p>
  </inserted>
  <ul>
    <p nid="t0:enr:14"><em>Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring),</em> That when the Senate recesses or adjourns on any day from Friday, January 4, 2013<removed sequence="8">,</removed> through Monday, January 21, 2013, on a motion offered pursuant to this concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or his designee, it stand recessed or adjourned until 12:00 noon on Monday, January 21, 2013, or such other time on that day as may be specified by its Majority Leader or his designee in the motion to recess or adjourn, or until the time of any reassembly pursuant to section 2 of this concurrent resolution, whichever occurs first; and that when the House adjourns on any legislative day from Friday, January 4, 2013, through Saturday, January 5, 2013, on a motion offered pursuant to this concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or his designee, it stand adjourned until 2:00 p.m. on Monday, January 14, 2013, or until the time of any reassembly pursuant to section 2 of this concurrent resolution, whichever occurs first.</p>
    <p nid="t0:enr:15" tracking-nids="t0:ats:13">Sec. 2.  The Majority Leader of the Senate and the Speaker of the House, or their respective designees, acting jointly after consultation with the Minority Leader of the Senate and the Minority Leader of the House, shall notify the Members of the Senate and House, respectively, to reassemble at such place and time as they may designate if, in their opinion, the public interest shall warrant it.</p>
  </ul>
  <inserted sequence="9">
    <p nid="t0:enr:16">Attest:</p>
    <p nid="t0:enr:17">Secretary of the Senate.</p>
    <p nid="t0:enr:18">Attest:</p>
    <p nid="t0:enr:19">Clerk of the House of Representatives.</p>
  </inserted>
</body>
