<?xml version="1.0"?>
<body status="eh" difference-size-chars="1078" percent-change="37" total-changes="8" previous-status="rh">
  <p nid="t0:eh:1" tracking-nids="t0:rh:1">HRES 66 <removed sequence="1">RH<p/><center><p nid="t0:rh:2">House Calendar No. 4</p></center><p/><center><p nid="t0:rh:3">113th CONGRESS</p></center><p/><center><p nid="t0:rh:4">1st Session</p></center><p/><center><p nid="t0:rh:5">H. RES. 66</p></center><p/><center><p nid="t0:rh:6">[Report No. 113-9]</p></center><p nid="t0:rh:7">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 273) to eliminate the 2013 statutory pay adjustment for Federal employees, and for other purposes.</p><p/><center><p nid="t0:rh:8">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</p></center><p/><h3 nid="t0:rh:9"><center><p nid="t0:rh:10">February 13, 2013</p></center></h3><p nid="t0:rh:11">Mr. WOODALL, from the Committee on Rules, reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be printed</p><hr/><p/><center><p nid="t0:rh:12">RESOLUTION</p></center>Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 273) to eliminate the 2013 statutory pay adjustment for Federal employees, and for other purposes</removed><inserted sequence="2">EH</inserted></p>
  <inserted sequence="3">
    <p/>
    <center>
      <p nid="t0:eh:2">H. Res. 66</p>
    </center>
    <p nid="t0:eh:3">
      <em>
        <center>
          <p nid="t0:eh:4">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</p>
        </center>
      </em>
    </p>
  </inserted>
  <p nid="t0:eh:5">
    <em>
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:eh:6"><inserted sequence="4">February 14, 2013</inserted>.</p>
      </center>
    </em>
  </p>
  <ul>
    <p nid="t0:eh:7"><em>Resolved,</em> That upon the adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 273) to eliminate the 2013 statutory pay adjustment for Federal employees. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform; and (2) one motion to recommit.</p>
    <p nid="t0:eh:8" tracking-nids="t0:rh:15">Sec. 2.  During any recess or adjournment of not more than three days, if in the opinion of the Speaker the public interest so warrants, then the Speaker or his designee, after consultation with the Minority Leader, may reconvene the House at a time other than that previously appointed, within the limits of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution, and notify Members accordingly.</p>
    <p nid="t0:eh:9" tracking-nids="t0:rh:16">Sec. 3.  It shall be in order at any time through the legislative day of February 15, 2013, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules, as though under clause 1 of rule XV, relating to a measure condemning the government of North Korea and its February 12, 2013<inserted sequence="5">,</inserted> test of a nuclear device.</p>
    <p nid="t0:eh:10" tracking-nids="t0:rh:17">Sec. 4.  On any legislative day during the period from February 16, 2013, through February 22, 2013--</p>
    <p nid="t0:eh:11" tracking-nids="t0:rh:18">(a) the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved; and</p>
    <p nid="t0:eh:12" tracking-nids="t0:rh:19">(b) the Chair may at any time declare the House adjourned to meet at a date and time, within the limits of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution, to be announced by the Chair in declaring the adjournment.</p>
    <p nid="t0:eh:13" tracking-nids="t0:rh:20">Sec. 5.  The Speaker may appoint Members to perform the duties of the Chair for the duration of the period addressed by section 4 of this resolution as though under clause 8(a) of rule I.</p>
  </ul>
  <p nid="t0:eh:14">
    <removed sequence="6">
      <p nid="t0:rh:21">House Calendar No. 4</p>
      <p/>
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:rh:22">113th CONGRESS</p>
      </center>
      <p/>
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:rh:23">1st Session</p>
      </center>
      <p/>
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:rh:24">H. RES. 66</p>
      </center>
      <p/>
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:rh:25">[Report No. 113-9]</p>
      </center>
      <p/>
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:rh:26">RESOLUTION</p>
      </center>
      <p nid="t0:rh:27">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 273) to eliminate the 2013 statutory pay adjustment for Federal employees, and for other purposes.</p>
      <hr/>
      <p/>
      <h3 nid="t0:rh:28">
        <center>
          <p nid="t0:rh:29">February 13, 2013</p>
        </center>
      </h3>
      <p/>
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:rh:30">Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be printed</p>
      </center>
    </removed>
    <inserted sequence="7">Attest:</inserted>
  </p>
  <inserted sequence="8">
    <p nid="t0:eh:15">Clerk.</p>
  </inserted>
</body>
