<?xml version="1.0"?>
<body status="rh" difference-size-chars="875" percent-change="21" total-changes="6" previous-status="ih">
  <p nid="t0:rh:1" tracking-nids="t0:ih:1">HR 235 <removed sequence="1">IH</removed><inserted sequence="2">RH</inserted></p>
  <inserted sequence="3">
    <p/>
    <center>
      <p nid="t0:rh:2">Union Calendar No. 3</p>
    </center>
  </inserted>
  <p/>
  <center>
    <p nid="t0:rh:3">113th CONGRESS</p>
  </center>
  <p/>
  <center>
    <p nid="t0:rh:4" tracking-nids="t0:ih:3">1st Session</p>
  </center>
  <p/>
  <center>
    <p nid="t0:rh:5" tracking-nids="t0:ih:4">H. R. 235</p>
  </center>
  <inserted sequence="4">
    <p/>
    <center>
      <p nid="t0:rh:6">[Report No. 113-5]</p>
    </center>
  </inserted>
  <p nid="t0:rh:7">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide grants to States to streamline State requirements and procedures for veterans with military emergency medical training to become civilian emergency medical technicians.</p>
  <p/>
  <center>
    <p nid="t0:rh:8" tracking-nids="t0:ih:6">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</p>
  </center>
  <p/>
  <h3 nid="t0:rh:9">
    <center>
      <p nid="t0:rh:10" tracking-nids="t0:ih:8">January 14, 2013</p>
    </center>
  </h3>
  <p nid="t0:rh:11" tracking-nids="t0:ih:9">Mr. KINZINGER of Illinois (for himself and Mrs. CAPPS) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce</p>
  <p/>
  <inserted sequence="5">
    <h3 nid="t0:rh:12">
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:rh:13">February 4, 2013</p>
      </center>
    </h3>
    <p nid="t0:rh:14">Additional sponsors: Mrs. CHRISTENSEN, Ms. SCHAKOWSKY, Mr. WAXMAN, Mr. PALLONE, Mr. DINGELL, Mr. HULTGREN, Mr. FARENTHOLD, Mr. YODER, Mr. SCHOCK, Mr. BURGESS, Mr. HANNA, Mr. BRALEY of Iowa, Mr. WITTMAN, Mr. MICHAUD, Mr. RAHALL, and Mr. RODNEY DAVIS of Illinois</p>
    <p/>
    <h3 nid="t0:rh:15">
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:rh:16">February 4, 2013</p>
      </center>
    </h3>
    <p nid="t0:rh:17">Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</p>
    <hr/>
  </inserted>
  <p/>
  <center>
    <p nid="t0:rh:18">A BILL</p>
  </center>
  <p nid="t0:rh:19" tracking-nids="t0:ih:11">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide grants to States to streamline State requirements and procedures for veterans with military emergency medical training to become civilian emergency medical technicians.</p>
  <ul>
    <p nid="t0:rh:20" tracking-nids="t0:ih:12">
      <em>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,</em>
    </p>
  </ul>
  <p tracking-nids="t0:ih:13"/>
  <h3 nid="t0:rh:21">SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.</h3>
  <ul>
    <p nid="t0:rh:22" tracking-nids="t0:ih:14">This Act may be cited as the &#x2018;Veteran Emergency Medical Technician Support Act of 2013&#x2019;.</p>
  </ul>
  <p tracking-nids="t0:ih:15"/>
  <h3 nid="t0:rh:23">SEC. 2. ASSISTING VETERANS WITH MILITARY EMERGENCY MEDICAL TRAINING TO MEET REQUIREMENTS FOR BECOMING CIVILIAN EMERGENCY MEDICAL TECHNICIANS.</h3>
  <ul>
    <p nid="t0:rh:24">(a) In General- Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<usc-reference title="42" section="243" paragraph=""><usc-reference title="42" section="243" paragraph="">42 U.S.C. 243</usc-reference></usc-reference> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 314 the following:</p>
  </ul>
  <p tracking-nids="t0:ih:17"/>
  <blockquote>
    <h3 nid="t0:rh:25">&#x2018;SEC. 315. ASSISTING VETERANS WITH MILITARY EMERGENCY MEDICAL TRAINING TO MEET REQUIREMENTS FOR BECOMING CIVILIAN EMERGENCY MEDICAL TECHNICIANS.</h3>
    <ul>
      <p nid="t0:rh:26" tracking-nids="t0:ih:18">&#x2018;(a) Program- The Secretary shall establish a program consisting of awarding demonstration grants to States to streamline State requirements and procedures in order to assist veterans who completed military emergency medical technician training while serving in the Armed Forces of the United States to meet certification, licensure, and other requirements applicable to becoming an emergency medical technician in the State.</p>
      <p nid="t0:rh:27" tracking-nids="t0:ih:19">&#x2018;(b) Use of Funds- Amounts received as a demonstration grant under this section shall be used to prepare and implement a plan to streamline State requirements and procedures as described in subsection (a), including by--</p>
      <ul>
        <p nid="t0:rh:28" tracking-nids="t0:ih:20">&#x2018;(1) determining the extent to which the requirements for the education, training, and skill level of emergency medical technicians in the State are equivalent to requirements for the education, training, and skill level of military emergency medical technicians; and</p>
        <p nid="t0:rh:29" tracking-nids="t0:ih:21">&#x2018;(2) identifying methods, such as waivers, for military emergency medical technicians to forego or meet any such equivalent State requirements.</p>
      </ul>
      <p nid="t0:rh:30" tracking-nids="t0:ih:22">&#x2018;(c) Eligibility- To be eligible for a grant under this section, a State shall demonstrate that the State has a shortage of emergency medical technicians.</p>
      <p nid="t0:rh:31" tracking-nids="t0:ih:23">&#x2018;(d) Report- The Secretary shall submit to the Congress an annual report on the program under this section.</p>
      <p nid="t0:rh:32" tracking-nids="t0:ih:24">&#x2018;(e) Funding- Of the amount authorized by section 751(j)(1) to be appropriated to carry out section 751 for fiscal year 2014, there is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2014 through 2018.&#x2019;.</p>
      <p nid="t0:rh:33">(b) Conforming Amendment- Section 751(j)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<usc-reference title="42" section="294a" paragraph="j_1"><usc-reference title="42" section="294a" paragraph="j_1">42 U.S.C. 294a(j)(1)</usc-reference></usc-reference>) is amended by striking &#x2018;There is authorized to be appropriated&#x2019; and inserting &#x2018;Subject to section 315(e), there is authorized to be appropriated&#x2019;.</p>
    </ul>
  </blockquote>
  <inserted sequence="6">
    <p nid="t0:rh:34">Union Calendar No. 3</p>
    <p/>
    <center>
      <p nid="t0:rh:35">113th CONGRESS</p>
    </center>
    <p/>
    <center>
      <p nid="t0:rh:36">1st Session</p>
    </center>
    <p/>
    <center>
      <p nid="t0:rh:37">H. R. 235</p>
    </center>
    <p/>
    <center>
      <p nid="t0:rh:38">[Report No. 113-5]</p>
    </center>
    <p/>
    <center>
      <p nid="t0:rh:39">A BILL</p>
    </center>
    <p nid="t0:rh:40">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide grants to States to streamline State requirements and procedures for veterans with military emergency medical training to become civilian emergency medical technicians.</p>
    <hr/>
    <p/>
    <h3 nid="t0:rh:41">
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:rh:42">February 4, 2013</p>
      </center>
    </h3>
    <p/>
    <center>
      <p nid="t0:rh:43">Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</p>
    </center>
  </inserted>
</body>
