<?xml version="1.0"?>
<body status="rfs" difference-size-chars="558" percent-change="28" total-changes="12" previous-status="ih">
  <p nid="t0:rfs:1" tracking-nids="t0:ih:1">HR 667 <changed sequence="1"><changed-from>IH</changed-from><changed-to>RFS</changed-to></changed></p>
  <p/>
  <center>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:2">113th CONGRESS</p>
  </center>
  <p/>
  <center>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:3" tracking-nids="t0:ih:3">1st Session</p>
  </center>
  <p/>
  <center>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:4" tracking-nids="t0:ih:4">H. R. 667</p>
  </center>
  <p/>
  <center>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:5">IN THE <changed sequence="2"><changed-from>HOUS</changed-from><changed-to>SENAT</changed-to></changed>E OF <removed sequence="3">REPRESENTATIVES<p/><h3 nid="t0:ih:7"><center><p nid="t0:ih:8">February 13, 2013</p></center></h3>Mr. MCCARTHY of California (for himself, Mr. CALVERT, Mr. SMITH of Texas, Mr. ROHRABACHER, Mr. PALAZZO, Mr. HALL, Mr. MCKEON, Mr. JORDAN, and Mr. SCHIFF) introduced the following bill; which was</removed><inserted sequence="4">THE UNITED STATES</inserted></p>
  </center>
  <inserted sequence="5">
    <p/>
    <h3 nid="t0:rfs:6">
      <center>
        <p nid="t0:rfs:7">February 26, 2013</p>
      </center>
    </h3>
  </inserted>
  <p nid="t0:rfs:8"><inserted sequence="6">Received; read twice and</inserted> referred to the Committee on <inserted sequence="7">Commerce, </inserted>Science, <removed sequence="8">Space, </removed>and T<removed sequence="9">echnology<hr/><p/><center><p nid="t0:ih:10">A BILL</p></center></removed><inserted sequence="10">ransportation</inserted></p>
  <inserted sequence="11">
    <hr/>
    <p/>
    <center>
      <p nid="t0:rfs:9">AN ACT</p>
    </center>
  </inserted>
  <p nid="t0:rfs:10">To redesignate the Dryden Flight Research Center as the Neil A. Armstrong Flight Research Center and the Western Aeronautical Test Range as the Hugh L. Dryden Aeronautical Test Range.</p>
  <ul>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:11" tracking-nids="t0:ih:12">
      <em>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,</em>
    </p>
  </ul>
  <p tracking-nids="t0:ih:13"/>
  <h3 nid="t0:rfs:12">SECTION 1. REDESIGNATION OF DRYDEN FLIGHT RESEARCH CENTER.</h3>
  <ul>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:13" tracking-nids="t0:ih:14">(a) Redesignation- The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) Hugh L. Dryden Flight Research Center in Edwards, California, is redesignated as the &#x2018;NASA Neil A. Armstrong Flight Research Center&#x2019;.</p>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:14" tracking-nids="t0:ih:15">(b) References- Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the flight research center referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the &#x2018;NASA Neil A. Armstrong Flight Research Center&#x2019;.</p>
  </ul>
  <p tracking-nids="t0:ih:16"/>
  <h3 nid="t0:rfs:15">SEC. 2. REDESIGNATION OF WESTERN AERONAUTICAL TEST RANGE.</h3>
  <ul>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:16" tracking-nids="t0:ih:17">(a) Redesignation- The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) Western Aeronautical Test Range in California is redesignated as the &#x2018;NASA Hugh L. Dryden Aeronautical Test Range&#x2019;.</p>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:17" tracking-nids="t0:ih:18">(b) References- Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the test range referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the &#x2018;NASA Hugh L. Dryden Aeronautical Test Range&#x2019;.</p>
  </ul>
  <inserted sequence="12">
    <p nid="t0:rfs:18">Passed the House of Representatives February 25, 2013.</p>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:19">Attest:</p>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:20">KAREN L. HAAS,</p>
    <p nid="t0:rfs:21">Clerk.</p>
  </inserted>
</body>
